Caitlin McQueen

970.443.3232 caitemcqueen@gmail.com caitlinmcqueen.me

Detailed event production and marketing professional who is an enthusiastic and positive advocate for musicians. Successful in de-escalating situations and handling time sensitive issues in high-pressure environments with 10 years of music event production and marketing experience. Ability to develop innovative marketing materials based on attraction rather than promotion.

- Create content for social media, digital resources, and newsletters. Employ boots on the ground marketing strategies
- Effectively manage ticketing platforms, websites, databases and artist relations
- Comprehensive understanding of backend logistics including offers, contracts and riders, show advance, and marketing timeline to show
- Resourceful when faced with unique and unexpected challenges during programming and planning phases

Technical Skills:

Show Advances and Backline

Contracts and Riders

Marketing on Social Media Platforms

Newsletter Systems (Mailchimp, Constant Contact etc)

Website Admin and Maintenance

Design Software including Photoshop

Microsoft Office including Excel

Experience

\sqrt{M}

Talent Buyer, Event Coordinator, Marketing

Mar 2014 - Jan 2019

Downtown Artery • Fort Collins, CO

Schedule programming and manage backend logistics and advances for all events. Manage social media accounts, Artery website, event builds for shows and events. Maintain database of 600+ artists.

- Booked, Planned and Executed over 175 successful events over the course of the 2018 year, and 100's more since 2014
- Worked internally and with partners to bring national touring headliners and emerging artists including: Kevin Morby, Anderson East, Secret Chiefs 3, Silversun Pickups, Slim Cessna's Auto Club, Paper Bird, Blitzen Trapper, SUSTO, The Wild Reeds, The Mountain Goats, Built To Spill, Third Eye Blind to our 270 capacity room
- Created marketing trade deals with radio and local publications including a yearly \$12,000 advertising budget with local newspaper in 2016, in exchange for hosting a monthly event. Renewed contract for 2017

Founder Oct 2016

Break Open: A Mental Health Festival • mentalhealthfestival.com

Conceptualized and founded a mental health festival designed to break down stigma and provide resources around mental health through workshops, panels, music collaborations and art. Was responsible for all programming and planning. Festival took place over 2 days bringing in over 250 people. Secured funding and sponsorship through UCHealth and other community partners.

Program Director

Mar 2012 - Dec 2014

Mishawaka Amphitheatre • Bellvue, CO

Administrated and fulfilled contract, rider obligations and settlement. Developed marketing and promotion strategies for upcoming events.

Liaison for four talent buyers from Boulder Theatre, Z2 Entertainment, Sweetwine Entertainment Group, and Cervantes, along with agents from WME, Paradigm, Windish Agency, and High Road Touring.

- Built events in ticketing system and coordinated pre-sale and on-sale date, time and release
- Managed post-contract bookings and non-technicial operations and logistics from conception to execution
- Gained experience in development of outdoor venue infrastructure and transportation with focus on public safety and environment sustainability
- Conceptualized and brought to fruition a successful brand for the Mishawaka Amphitheatre. The seasonal
 t-shirt the team created, sold over 300 during the summer season. The design was recognized as a band and
 fan favorite, having to reorder due to high demand

Education

Colorado State University

Aug 2007- May 2011

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration Concentration in Management Certificate in Entrepreneurship

Florence University of Arts

May 2008 - Aug 2009

Courses in Culinary Arts and Photography

California State University Chico

Aug 2006 - May 2007

Other Industry and Community Service

Fort Collins Music Experiment (FOCOMX) 2018-19

Booking committee and marketing

Fort Collins Music Task Force 2018

Coalition to advise City of Fort Collins policy on music and nightlife

Educational Coordinator, SPOKESBUZZ 2012-14

Intern, Greeley Stampede 2010

Staff Writer, The Rocky Mountain Collegian 2008-09

